Finding Aid for William Edward Wise visual materials collection, 1948-1955
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
William Edward Wise visual materials collection
1948-1955
Wise, William Edward
2014119 Aa 2
William Edward Wise was a student at the University of Michigan and graduated from the College of Architecture in 1951. He was a photographer for the Michiganensian yearbook and the collection documents football games and other campus events, 1948-1955.
0.4 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
This collection (donor no. 11057 ) was received in January 2014.
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open without restriction.
William Edward Wise was a student at the University of Michigan and graduated from the College of Architecture in 1951. He was a photographer for the Michiganensian yearbook. His wife, Cecilia Zambiasi also graduated from the University of Michigan with an MA in 1950.
The William Edward Wise collection documents the University of Michigan campus and events, 1948-1955 and consists of two series, Negatives and Prints. The Negatives series consists of 29 envelopes of 4x5 black and white negatives arranged in two subseries, Football, 1948-1951 and Other campus photographs, 1948-1955. The Football subseries consists of ten envelopes of negatives, four of which pertain to the 1951 Rose Bowl. The Other campus photographs subseries contains images of student groups, dances, campus landscapes and buildings, and other campus events during Wise's tenure as a student from 1948-1951. One additional envelope depicts the University of Michigan's North Campus in 1955. The Prints series contain four folders of prints relating to campus buildings, groups shots, sports and student life. Many of the prints appear to have been developed from the negatives in the collection.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Clergy--United States.; First Unitarian Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Imperialism.; India.; Sunderland, Jabez Thomas, 1842-1936.; Unitarian churches--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Unitarian Universalist churches--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Universalist churches--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Western Unitarian Conference.
Contributors:
Abernethy, Alonzo, 1836-1915.; Aked, Charles Frederic, 1864-1941.; Allen, Joseph Henry, 1820-1898.; American Anti-Imperialist League.; American League to Limit Armaments.; Ames, Charles Gordon, 1828-1912.; Andrews, C. F. (Charles Freer), 1871-1940.; Angell, George T. (George Thorndike), 1823-1909.; Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.; Bagley, John Judson, 1832-1881.; Baldwin, William Henry, 1826-1909.; Batchelor, George, 1836-1923.; Blackwell, Alice Stone, 1857-1950.; Bose, Jagadis Chandra, 1858-1937.; Bose, Sudhindra, 1883-; Bowie, W. Copeland (William Copeland); Brigham, Charles H. (Charles Henry), 1820-1879.; Canada India League.; Chadwick, John White, 1840-1904.; Chapin, Augusta J., d. 1905.; Chatterjee, Ramananda, 1865-1943.; Clarke, James Freeman, 1810-1888.; Collyer, Robert, 1823-1912.; Cooke, George Willis, 1848-1923.; Crane, Augustus Warren, 1868-1937.; Crane, Caroline Bartlett, 1858-1935.; Crooker, Joseph Henry, 1850-1931.; Das, Taraknath, 1884-1958.; De Normandie, James, 1836-1924.; Drummond, James, 1835-1924.; Durant, Will, 1885-1981.; Eliot, Samuel Atkins, 1862-1950.; Everett, Charles Carroll, 1829-1900.; Ferris, Woodbridge N., 1853-1928.; Foote, Henry Wilder, 1875-1964.; Friends of Freedom for India.; Friends of India's Independence.; Gandhi, Mahatma, 1869-1948.; Gannett, Lewis, 1891-1966.; Gannett, William C. (William Channing), 1840-1923.; Garrison, William Lloyd, 1838-1909.; Gregg, Richard Bartlett, 1885-; Hale, Edward Everett, 1822-1909.; Hay, John, 1838-1905.; Herford, Brooke, 1830-1903.; Hindustan Association of America.; Hoar, George Frisbie, 1826-1904.; Holmes, John Haynes, 1879-1964.; India Academy of America.; India Independence League of America.; Indian National Congress. American Branch.; India Society of America.; Indian Independence League.; Ingersoll, Robert Green, 1833-1899.; Jackson, Helen Hunt, 1830-1885.; Japan Society (New York, N.Y.); Jones, Jenkin Lloyd, 1843-1918.; Jordan, David Starr, 1851-1931.; King, Judson, 1872-1958.; Krishna Menon, V. K. (Vengalil Krishnan), 1897-1974.; Ladd, George Trumbull, 1842-1921.; Lajpat Rai, Lala, 1865-1928.; Mabie, Henry Clay, 1847-1918.; McMillan, James, 1838-1902.; Manny, Frank Addison, 1868-1954.; Martineau, James, 1805-1900.; Mead, Edwin Doak, 1849-1937.; Mead, Lucia True Ames, 1856-1936.; Michigan Authors' Association.; Morehouse, Henry Lyman, 1834-1917.; National Liberal League.; Nehru, Jawaharlal, 1889-1964.; Northrup, George Washington, 1826-1900.; Palmer, Thomas Witherell, 1830-1913.; Peabody, Francis Greenwood, 1847-1936.; Phelps, Myron H. (Myron Henry), 1856-1916.; Reid, Gilbert, 1857-1927.; Reid, Whitelaw, 1837-1912.; Savage, Minot Judson, 1841-1918.; Schurz, Carl, 1829-1906.; Shippen, Joseph, 1839-1923.; Shippen, Rush Rhees, b. 1828.; Simmons, Henry M. (Henry Martyn), 1841-1905.; Singh, Hajom Kissor, 1865-1923.; Society for the Advancement of India.; Strong, Sydney, 1860-1938.; Sumner, William Graham, 1840-1910.; Tagore, Rabindranath, 1861-1941.; Toy, Crawford Howell, 1836-1919.; Villard, Fanny Garrison, 1844-1928.; Villard, Oswald Garrison, 1872-1949.; Washington, Booker T., 1856-1915.; Wendte, Charles W. (Charles William), 1844-1931.; Willard, Frances E. (Frances Elizabeth), 1839-1898.; Winchell, Alexander, 1824-1891.; Winslow, Erving, 1839-1922.; Wise, Stephen S. (Stephen Samuel), 1874-1949.
Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Sermons.
- Negatives, 1948-1955
  - Football, 1948-1951
    - Michigan versus Dartmouth, 1950 (Box 1)
    - Michigan versus Illinois, 1950 (Box 1)
    - Michigan versus Indiana, 1948 (Box 1)
    - Michigan versus Indiana, 1950 (Box 1)
    - Michigan versus Michigan State, 1950 (Box 1)
    - Michigan versus Northwestern, 1950 (Box 1)
    - Rose Bowl, Michigan versus California, 1951 (Box 1)
    - Rose Bowl, Spectator shots, etc., 1951 (Box 1)
    - Tournament of Roses Parade, 1951; 2 envelopes (Box 1)
  - Other Campus Photographs, 1948-1955
    - A 5,6,7,8,9,10 problems, 1951 (Box 1)
    - American Institute of Architects (AIA) meeting and golf, summer 1950 (Box 1)
    - Campus pix, 1948; 2 envelopes (Box 1)
    - Chinese students, Martha Cook Assembly Fun Nite, Men's Glee Club, Ballet Group, 1948 (Box 1)
    - Greenwich Party, APX Fraternity, 1949 (Box 1)
    - Group shots Michiganensian, 1950 (Box 1)
    - International Center 10th Anniversary, 1948 (Box 1)
    - J-Hop, 1949; 2 envelopes (Box 1)
    - Masquerade of the Heads, 1948 (Box 1)
    - Michigan winter scenes, Zambiasi farm, 1951 (Box 1)
    - Newman Club, girl's chair, men's chair, baby sitting, 1949 (Box 1)
    - Pan-Hellenic Recognition Night, Painting pix Mrs. Brown, Judiciary Council -- Women's, European Club, 1949 (Box 1)
    - Professor Weaver's Class, professional fraternities, 1948 (Box 1)
    - Sailing Regatta, 1950 (Box 1)
    - Snow photos, campus at night, 1950 (Box 1)
    - University of Michigan North Campus, 1955 (Box 1)
    - Winter carnival, 1949 (Box 1)
- Prints, undated
  - Buildings on campus (Box 1)
  - Group shots (Box 1)
  - Sports (Box 1)
  - Student life (Box 1)